tnvacation.com 2009-06-03

# Tennessee Vacation - The State's Official Travel Planning Website

### Information Collection and Use

The Tennessee Department of Tourist Development (TDTD) collects information from its users at several different points on the TDTD website, [www.tnvacation.com](http://www.tnvacation.com/). If you choose to offer the TDTD your e-mail address, name, address, phone or comments, TDTD will store this information in a tourism database and it will be available to tourism facilities. Information about contests, surveys, special offers and savings and newsletters may be sent to you by TDTD and/or TDTD's tourism partners. Out of respect for the privacy of TDTD's website users, TDTD will provide users the option not to receive these types of communications. Please see the opt-out provision below.

### Order

TDTD requests information from website users on its order form. Here a user must provide contact information (like name and shipping address). This information is used to fill TDTD's customer orders. If TDTD has trouble processing an order, this contact information is used to get in touch with the user.

### Cookies

A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's hard drive containing information about the user. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on TDTD's site. For instance, by setting a cookie on the TDTD site, the user would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on the TDTD website. If a user rejects the cookie, they may still use the TDTD website. The only drawback to this is that the user will be limited in some areas of the TDTD website. For example, the user will not be able to participate in any of TDTD's sweepstakes, contests or monthly drawings that take may place or use the trip planner feature. Cookies can also enable TDTD to track and target the interests of its users to enhance the experience on the TDTD website.

### Log Files

TDTD uses IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.

### Content and Information Disclaimer

Content and information contained in this website has been compiled by TDTD, based on data submitted directly from local tourism promotion agencies and business entities. While every effort is made to ensure the accuracy of this information, all data is subject to change without notice. Travelers are advised to contact individual businesses or organizations to obtain information to their satisfaction before traveling. TDTD does not endorse or recommend any specific facility, attraction or organization contained in this site.

### Links

This website contains links to other sites. Please be aware that TDTD is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. TDTD encourages its users to be aware when they leave TDTD's site, to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this website.

### Surveys & Contests

From time-to-time the TDTD website requests information from users via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. During registration a user is required to give their contact information (such as name and email address). Other information requested may include contact information (shipping address and phone number), and demographic information (such as zip code, age level). It is optional for the user to provide demographic information (such as income level and gender), but encouraged so TDTD can provide a more personalized experience on the TDTD website. Contact information will be used to notify the winners and award prizes. TDTD will also share contact information with companies who partner with TDTD for the contests. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site.

### Website Comment Posting

Content â€“ Comments should focus on the personalities, locations, stories and opinions surrounding the history, heritage, themes and topics of this website. Try to keep comments concise. Comments must not be obscene, profane, sexually explicit, libelous, slanderous, defamatory, harmful, threatening, illegal or knowingly false. Please use the proper grammar to express yourself. No website links or advertisements can be posted. Disclaimer â€“ The Tennessee Department of Tourist Development (TDTD) is not liable for the opinions or validity of any outside sources cited of comments posted. TDTD has authority to post or remove comments at its discretion. Comments will be posted on the website with only the name you enter, without the eMail address. Your name and eMail address are still required when initially leaving your comment, so that TDTD can contact you. Your eMail address will not be sold to a third party for marketing purposes. By posting to this forum, you assume responsibility for your communications and the consequences of posting them. Note: There will be a delay period between submission and display of accepted items on the website.

### Special Offers

TDTD will occasionally send information on products, services, special deals, and a newsletter to email addresses collected on the site. Out of respect for the privacy of TDTD's users TDTD presents the option to not receive these types of communications. Please see the TDTD opt-out below.

### Correction/Updating Personal Information

If a user's personally identifiable information changes (such as your zip code), or if a user no longer desires the TDTD website, travel service, TDTD will endeavor to provide a way to correct, update or remove that user's personal data previously provided TDTD.

### Opt-out

A user who no longer wishes to receive the TDTD newsletter or promotional materials from TDTD's partners may opt-out of receiving these communications by clicking the unsubscribe link located on the e-mail received by user.

If TDTD decides to change this privacy policy, TDTD will post such changes on TDTD's privacy page so users are always aware of what information is being collected, how it will be used, and under what circumstances, if any, TDTD will disclose it. If at any point TDTD decides to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, TDTD will notify users by way of an email. Users will have a choice as to whether or not TDTD may use their information in this or in a different manner. TDTD will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.

If you have comments or questions regarding the Department of Tourist Development web site privacy policy, contact [tourdev@tn.gov](mailto:tourdev@tn.gov).
